<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Smonff Shurfs]]></title>
  <link href="http://smonff.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://smonff.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-19T01:11:23+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://smonff.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Smonff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Google RSS Reader era]]></title>
    <link href="http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/19/post-google-rss-reader-era/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T14:29:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/19/post-google-rss-reader-era</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey, <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.fr/2013/03/a-second-spring-of-cleaning.html">Google announce it will close it&#8217;s RSS <em>Reader</em></a>.
So what? Do we really need it anyway? You can find plenty of friendly and beautiful clones of <em>Reader</em>, like <a href="http://feedly.com">Feedly</a>
or <a href="http://theoldreader.com/">The Old Reader</a>. Both of two seems nice. Both of two are clearly Readers clones and alternatives.</p>

<p>I first tryed <em>The Old Reader</em> for about a month, before all the <em>Reader</em> drama when Google announce it&#8217;s death. It was so slow
that I was feeling asleep as waiting for a feed to load. I don&#8217;t notice anything particular in comparaison with Reader. The only thing is that you got some more hype <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajax_(programming">AJAX stuff</a> plus some special <em>social bits</em> that makes possible to share more fecal feeds with your friends. Just as if your friends weren&#8217;t full-time busy by their own feeds.</p>

<p>This is a very important thing. <em>Feeds</em>&#8230; Hey, if you want to share feeds with friends, please, open it, don&#8217;t close it for privacy reasons, use a tool without any account or password, open a Wiki or whatever.</p>

<p>Then, when the Reader tragedy came, I&#8217;ve tryed <a href="http://feedly.com">Feedly</a>. Honestly, it seems wonderful. I&#8217;ve liked the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.devhd.feedly">Android App</a>, hey it&#8217;s a wonderful tool. Everybody were recommanding it on the internet. It seems it&#8217;s gonna be my new RSS feeds reader. But this morning I read an <a href="https://twitter.com/LeaVerou/status/313394360412672000">interesting Lea Verou Tweet</a>:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="fr"><p>So it looks like @<a href="https://twitter.com/feedly">feedly</a> is the most popular alternative, but it doesn’t seem to have any business model, so it could disappear at any time.</p>&mdash; Lea Verou (@LeaVerou) <a href="https://twitter.com/LeaVerou/status/313394360412672000">17 mars 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://smonff.github.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>So. What if it will be true. What if Feedly disappear soon? It seems a good solution would be to select a good RSS feed free software like [Tiny Tiny RSS]](http://tt-rss.org/), pick-up a random server, set-up a LAMP environment and make things by yourself (as describe in <a href="http://www.sebsauvage.net/rhaa/index.php?2013/03/15/17/15/39-arretez-de-pleurer-google-reader-hebergez-un-lecteur-rss-chez-vous">this sebsauvage post</a>&#8230; I mention <em>Tiny Tiny RSS</em> because it&#8217;s realy simple, customizable and feature <a href="http://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdfilter=rss&amp;fdid=org.fox.ttrss">a great Android client that communicate with an API on your server&#8217;s instance</a> featuring interesting synchronisation stuff.</p>

<p>You would not get a prettiest UI/UX as the Feedly one, you won&#8217;t get the Google Reader goodies, but your data will be safe. And you can hack your UI as you want&#8230; Ok, Reader was pretty, but we don&#8217;t like proprietary software. We would like to keep our feeds free, we don&#8217;t need these <em>closing source</em> web-apps that starve our feeds&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Need a Markdown editor for Android with Github support]]></title>
    <link href="http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/18/need-a-markdown-editor-for-android-with-github-support/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-18T14:44:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/18/need-a-markdown-editor-for-android-with-github-support</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my second blog post and I still need a Markdown editor for Android with Github support.</p>

<p>Start to think to write it but I don&#8217;t need yet another side project. My phone is not rooted and can&#8217;t find a simple and free tool that support Markdown + Github.</p>

<p>But suddenly, I simply remember that you can edit Markdown files directly in Github&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/11/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-11T14:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://smonff.github.com/blog/2013/03/11/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my <a href="http://smonff@github.com">new blog</a>. It&#8217;s made with <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> and totally (software and content) <a href="https://github.com/smonff/smonff.github.com">open source</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
